PAKIZE BOZKURT

| Birmingham, UK | 07309 234783

pakiozihak@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/PakizeBozkurt | github.com/PakizeBozkurt

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a bi-lingual and masters degree educated aspiring software developer. I have recently graduated from an intensive software development programme called CodeYourFuture which is an 11-month programme with a minimum commitment of 25 hours per week predominantly working on (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, and SQL). I have thoroughly enjoyed the course and you can see evidence of my work and projects using the links above. Before re;ocating to the UK I worked as a philosophy teacher for 15 years which means I bring a unique perspective and strong problem-solving abilities to software development alongside a strong set of soft skills.

I am currently seeking my first opportunity in software development. I am available immediately, have full right to work in the UK and am seeking roles with On-Site, Hybrid or Remote.

EXPERIENCE

Study Buddies(Final project) at Code Your Future, Full Stack Developer, May 2022 - Mar 2023

- Developed a Study Buddies app using JS, Node.js, and React within four weeks.
- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers and a project manager to successfully deploy.
- Conducted user(27) research, receiving 85% ratings for user-friendliness and excellence.
- Managed project repositories, tracked 4 milestones, and performed thorough 15 code reviews.

Link: Study-Buddies Repo & Deployed Link

Relocated & Adaptation, Jan 2020 - May 2022

- Relocated to the UK in 2020 and dedicated time to learning the English language.
- Actively participated in volunteer work for the British Heart Foundation 2021 to 2023.

15 Years of Experience as a Group of Philosophy Teacher, Turkey, Sep 2005 - Jan 2020

- Taught philosophy, psychology, sociology, logic, and democracy to high school students for 15 years.
- Managed philosophy classes, guiding over 600 students to achieve their academic goals.
- Organised 15 philosophy clubs and activities, encouraging over 200 students to engage in in-depth studies
- Stayed updated with current developments in philosophy through professional development, attending over 20 seminars.

PAKIZE BOZKURT

| Birmingham, UK | 07309 234783

pakiozihak@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/PakizeBozkurt | github.com/PakizeBozkurt

EDUCATION & TRAININGS

- Graduated Full Stack Web Development-Program, CodeYourFuture, Birmingham, UK May 2022 Apr 2023.
- Erasmus Project Training, Turkey, Nov 2019- Dec 2020
- MA, Philosophy, Gazi University, Turkey Sep 2013 Jun 2016
- Information Technologies Teacher Course, Fatih Project, Turkey, Oct 2012-Jan 2013
- BA, Teaching Philosophy(Group of,) Gazi University*(Gazi is ranked 1st in Turkey education.)
- Critical Thinking Strategies For Better Decisions (NASBA)
- Conflict with Emotional Intelligence (Udemy)
- Communicate Effectively at Work (Google)
- Problem Solving (Udemy)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Public Speaking Engagements

- Tech Wednesday Event (International Women's Month), March 2023
- Delivered a motivational speech titled "Empowering Women in Tech: My Journey"
- Inspired 40 participants, encouraging them to pursue their passion for technology and overcome challenges.

Attending Panel

- Code Your Future 'Women In Tech' Panel, April 2023
- Participated as the 2nd panellist, sharing valuable insights into my coding journey.
- Engaged in discussions about the challenges and opportunities for women in the tech industry.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

 React.js & MongoDB, Created 3 contact cards with React.js. Implemented databases with MongoDB.

Link: HR Contacts Repo & Deployed Link

• **JS & API**, Created 5 jokes with 5 images a fun app for developers at the HackTheMindlands event in 2022.

Link: hck2022 Repo & Deployed Link